so we have seen that using the RFP and
something like tomasulo's algorithm we
can enforce the order of dependencies on
registers between instructions the
question still remains what about memory
access ordering we have load and store
instructions do they really need to be
done strictly in program order or can we
do something about reordering them too
so far we have eliminated control
dependencies using branch prediction
eliminated false dependencies on
registers that these dependencies that
go through registers and we have
eliminated the false dependencies
through register renaming next we learn
how to obey read after write register
dependencies or through dependencies and
we do that through Tomasulo like
scheduling so we have instructions
waiting reservation stations until their
dependencies have been satisfied and
then they can proceed to execution out
of program order note that the data
dependence handling that we have done so
far however is only for register
dependencies that is when one
instruction is producing a value in a
register that another is going to be
using but what about memory dependencies
if we have a store and then allowed
there could also be a dependence between
the memory value written by the store
and then the value read by the load if
these two addresses are the same address
then actually the load needs to get the
value from the store and in which case
we should be doing them in order however
if these two addresses are not the same
just like with registers we actually
don't need to maintain the program order
between these accesses however we have
not seen anything that can handle out of
order execution of memory instructions